Superbad. Superdad.
Despicable Me is a family, comedy, animation film directed by Chris Renaud.
Villainous Gru lives up to his reputation as a despicable, deplorable and downright
unlikable guy when he hatches a plan to steal the moon from the sky.
But he has a tough time staying on task after three orphans land in his care.
Gru (voice), played by Steve Carell.
Vector (voice), played by Jason Segel.
Margo (voice), played by Miranda Cosgrove.
Edith (voice), played by Dana Gaier.
Agnes (voice), played by Elsie Fisher.
Dr. Nefario (voice), played by Russell Brand.
Despicable Me is a 2010 American animated comedy film directed by Chris Renaud and Pierre
Coffin and written by Cinco Paul and Ken Daurio from a story by Sergio Pablos.
Produced by Illumination Entertainment as its debut feature film, it stars the voices of Steve Carell, Jason Segel,
Russell Brand, Kristen Wiig, Miranda Cosgrove, Will Arnett, Danny McBride, Jack McBrayer, and Julie Andrews.
The story follows Gru, a longtime supervillain who adopts three orphan girls to use as pawns in
a villainous scheme but reluctantly develops an emotional attachment to them.
Development of Despicable Me began when Pablos pitched the idea about a main character having
villainous attributes to producer Chris Meledandri following Illumination's foundation in 2007.
The film was announced in 2008, with much of its creative team attached.
Animation was provided by Paris-based studio Mac Guff.
Pharrell Williams and Heitor Pereira composed the film's score, with
original songs written and performed by the former.
Despicable Me debuted at the Annecy International Animated Film Festival on June 9, 2010, and
was theatrically released in the United States on July 9 by Universal Pictures.
The film received positive reviews from critics and earned $543 million
worldwide, becoming the ninth-highest-grossing film of 2010.
It was nominated for Best Animated Feature Film at the Golden Globe Awards, BAFTA Awards and
Annie Awards, and won Favorite Animated Movie at the 2011 Kids' Choice Awards.
Despicable Me began a successful franchise which includes six
succeeding films, beginning with Despicable Me 2 in 2013.
The film explores themes of moon, parent child
relationship, orphanage, villain, adoptive father.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.